HONG PHUC THAI Cobol | Java Developer

641.819.2508 • phucthaihg@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/phucthaihg/ https://www.phucthaihg.site/

Senior software engineer with over 13 years of experience in the Insurance, Healthcare, and Banking domain. Have worked on projects to modernize, customize the core legacy systems, and integrate with other technologies. Experience in all phases of the software development life cycle (SDLC). Strong problem-solving, communication, analytical, and team leadership skills. Excellent in IBM technologies like mainframe, z/OS, IBM i Series, AS400, COBOL, CICS, JCL, SQL, DB2, VSAM, CL, RPGLE, and other technologies like JAVA, RESTful API, SOAP API, SOA, microservices, and more

SKILLS

Languages: COBOL, JCL, CICS, CL, SQL, RPGLE, Java

Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON, XML Web Services: RESTful API, SOAP API Frameworks: Spring Boot, JSP, NodeJS Databases: DB2, MySQL, MongoDB

Platforms: Mainframe, z/OS, IBM i Series, AS400, AWS: EC2, RDS, S3, Lambda, DynamoDB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tanisha System Inc / Wipro, Iselin, New Jersey 11/2023 – Present

KForce Inc, Tampa, Florida 01/2023 – 10/2023

Mainframe Developer

- Delivered professional services to Humana Inc., overseeing technical leadership of a team within an onshore-offshore model following Agile principles and SCRUM methodologies.
- Participated in projects to modernize healthcare operations, transitioning from mainframe to the Azure Cloud platform
- Involved in the end-to-end process, including designing, developing, testing, implementing, and maintaining healthcare applications
- A diverse set of technologies used, including Mainframe, z/OS, COBOL, JCL, CICS, DB2, SQL, z/OS connect, FileAid, AbendAid, EXPEDITER, CA7, FTP, MVS, ISPF, TSO, JSON, IDMS, microservices, Kafka, RESTful API, SNOW, ISPW, PLATINUM, and more

PRIME CONSULTING SERVICES LTD, Singapore 10/2018 - 04/2022

Application Consultant

- Delivered professional services to Prudential Singapore, contributing to the customization of their life and annuities insurance system operating on IBM i Series / AS400 through various projects
- Engaged in all stages of the software development life cycle (SDLC) within Agile and Kanban principles
- Collaborated with the Business Analyst team and users to clarify requirements from functional specifications, subsequently translating them into technical solutions specified in technical documentation. Primarily focused on functionalities such as configuring New Products, Policy Servicing, Claims, Finance, Payment services, and more
- Involved in the design, development, testing, implementation, and maintenance of applications, while also providing support for User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and handling production incidents

• A diverse set of technologies used, including IBM iSeries, AS400, COBOL/400, CL, RPGLE, DB2, SQL, online and batch job processing, IBM MQ, microservices, RESTful API, and more

AIA SINGAPORE, Singapore 12/2017 – 10/2018

Technical Analyst

- Contributed to internal projects to customize the life and annuities insurance system on IBM i Series / AS400.
- Engaged in all aspects of the software development life cycle (SDLC) following Kanban principles
- Collaborated with the Business Analyst team and users to elucidate requirements from functional specifications, subsequently translating them into technical solutions outlined in technical specifications. Primarily focused on functionalities such as claims and payment services
- Involved in the design, development, testing, implementation, and maintenance of applications
- Provided support for User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and addressed production incidents
- A diverse set of technologies used, including IBM iSeries, AS400, COBOL/400, CL, RPGLE, DB2, SQL, online and batch job processing, IBM MQ, microservices, RESTful API, and more

BLUE STAR INFOSTACK SOLUTIONS PTE LTD, Singapore 10/2017 – 12/2017

U3 Infotech, Singapore 2/2016 – 10/2017

Application Analyst

- Enhanced AVIVA Singapore's life and annuities insurance system on IBM i Series / AS400
- Engaged in all stages of the software development life cycle (SDLC) following Kanban principles
- Collaborated with the Business Analyst team and users to clarify requirements from functional specifications, translating them into technical solutions in technical specifications. Mainly focused on functionalities such as setting up new products and claims
- Involved in the design, development, testing, implementation, and maintenance of applications
- Provided support for User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and addressed production incidents
- A diverse set of technologies used, including IBM iSeries, AS400, COBOL/400, CL, RPGLE, DB2, SQL, online and batch job processing, IBM MQ, microservices, RESTful API, and more

GMA Tech Consulting Sdn Bhd, Malaysia 07/2015 - 02/2016

Senior Software Engineer

- Enhanced the life and annuities insurance system at Great Eastern Life, operating on IBM i Series / AS400
- Engaged in all facets of the software development life cycle (SDLC) following Kanban principles
- Collaborated with the Business Analyst team and users to elucidate requirements from functional specifications, subsequently translating them into technical solutions detailed in technical specifications. Mainly concentrated on functionalities such as setting up new products and report generation
- Involved in the design, development, testing, implementation, and maintenance of applications
- Provided support for User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and addressed production incidents
- A diverse set of technologies used, including IBM iSeries, AS400, COBOL/400, CL, RPGLE, DB2, SQL, online and batch job processing, and more

CSC Vietnam Technology, Vietnam 07/2011 - 08/2015 Senior Software Engineer

• Modernized the core legacy insurance system for Zurich Farmers - USA and customized the life and annuities insurance systems for AIA - Singapore and Phu Hung Life - Vietnam

- Played the role of a team lead, providing guidance to team members on daily tasks to enhance their understanding of the system, improve technical skills, and expand domain knowledge
- Assigned tasks to team members and facilitated code reviews to ensure the quality of deliveries
- Leveraged a wide range of technologies, including mainframe, z/OS, IBM i Series, AS400, COBOL, CICS, JCL, SQL, DB2, VSAM, COBOL/400, RPGLE, CL, CA7, IBM SPUFI, IBM ENDEVOR, Xpediter, Platinum, Syncsort, DFSORT, IBM MQ, online and batch job processing, MVS, ISPF, TSO, Java, RESTful API, SOAP API, microservices, and Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA) under Agile Application Development, Scrum, and Kanban methodologies

CSC Vietnam Technology, Vietnam 07/2010 - 02/2011 Software Engineer

- Modernized the core legacy banking system for FSS Banking USA
- Leveraged a wide range of technologies, including mainframe, z/OS, IBM i Series, AS400, COBOL, CICS, JCL, SQL, DB2, VSAM, COBOL/400, RPGLE, CL, CA7, IBM SPUFI, IBM ENDEVOR, Xpediter, Platinum, Syncsort, DFSORT, IBM MQ, online and batch job processing, MVS, ISPF, TSO, Java, SOAP API, microservices, and Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA) under Agile Application Development, Scrum, and Kanban methodologies

IACP Asia Co., LTD, Vietnam 07/2009 – 07/2010 Software Engineer

- Enhanced core insurance system for AXA Finance
- Contributed to the development team to administer coding changes
- Performed unit tests and documented test data
- Prepared documentation for system enhancements
- Technologies used: mainframe, z/OS, IBM i Series, AS400, COBOL, CICS, JCL, SQL, DB2, TSO, VSAM, CA7, IBM SPUFI, IBM ENDEVOR, Xpediter, Platinum, Syncsort, DFSORT, IBM MQ, online and batch job processing, MVS, ISPF, TSO

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

Maharishi International University, Fairfield, Iowa, 04/2022 – expected completion 01/2024

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

University of Natural Sciences, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam, 09/2005 – 09/2009

LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

FLMI Level 1: Insurance Fundamentals, Issued by LOMA, Aug 2018

AINS 21: Property and Liability Insurance Principles, Issued by The Institutes, Sep 2012

COBOL Programming with VSCode, Issued by IBM, Dec 2022

https://www.credly.com/badges/db8e7d11-5c58-4871-9a80-fc019cdd3529/linked in profile

Modernize Applications with IBM CICS, Issued by IBM, Dec 2022

https://www.credly.com/badges/9e465a0a-884f-4419-abcb-13a6667c847f/linked in profile

Java 8 Essential Training, Issued by LinkedIn, Nov 2022

https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/986c96c8b09199d2a88e1b27a7e23fed4002cc38e047f0d909f0a3100a8156c3